Good to be with you.
I'm Tony Dokoupil.
The breaking news right now.
Double trouble-- millions bracing for dangerous weather on both coasts as a nor'easter could slam the East Coast with tropical-storm-force winds and heavy rain as Hurricane Polo spins out there in the Pacific, turning into one of the strongest storms ever.
Rob Marciano in the storm zone.
Also developing tonight President Trump's highly anticipated summit with China's Xi Jinping.
Another military fighter jet crashes during a training mission-- the condition of the pilots tonight, the crew safely ejecting before it slams to the ground.
What went wrong?
Bombshell testimony at the murder trial of that former American Idol contestant accused of killing his wife in their bed while their children slept nearby.
What his former girlfriend said on the stand today.
And why Dolly Parton's manager has filed for a restraining order against the man who announced her death just weeks ago.
Rollercoaster lawsuits-- more than a hundred people say they suffered traumatic brain injuries from this California thrill ride.
A close call on a Utah freeway, lightning nearly striking this truck.
And the good stuff, the historic home run ball and the birthday girl, who threw it back.
COMMENTATOR: And throwing it back.
Oh my goodness.
ANNOUNCER: From CBS News headquarters in New York, this is the CBS Evening News with Tony Dokoupil.
Good evening.
Great to have you with us on a Wednesday night.
We begin with dual updates on a series of major storms off both coasts.
In the Atlantic, high winds already whipping up the surf ahead of what is now expected to become a nor'easter.
Coastal flood alerts are already in place from the Carolinas up to the Jersey Shore ahead of landfall this weekend, while over in the Pacific, Hurricane Polo, a Category 4 storm, is expected to impact the California coast in the coming days.
And for Hawaii's Big Island, forecasters are warning of the potential for catastrophic flooding and mudslides from what's expected to become another major hurricane.
Rob Marciano tracking it all, as always, starting with the conditions off the East Coast right now.
Rob, how's it looking?
Hey, Tony, well, pretty much the same it's been all day, which is a relentlessly consistent barrage of wind and water.
I mean, look at that ocean.
It just looks like an absolute washing machine.
It's been pummeling this coastline all day long in Virginia, North Carolina, where they lost a lot of real estate with the storms last year.
And this coastal storm is now just beginning to strengthen.
Pounding surf pummeled Virginia Beach today, powered by winds reaching 45 miles per hour, bending trees, and whipping through this nearly deserted beach town.
Nearby Norfolk, home to the largest US Naval base in the world, they're dealing with storm tide flooding.
A lot of the floodgates here in Norfolk have been closed out ahead of this storm.
For the water that does actually seep into the city, that's one of 14 pumping stations that they have to get water back out into the river.
This slow-moving storm is expected to pack a one-two punch as it churns up the coast.
Strong winds and full moon tides have the potential to bring coastal flooding and severe beach erosion.
That's good.
Go ahead.
ROB MARCIANO: Residents in Massachusetts are preparing for the onslaught.
Sometimes these storms take a turn for the worst.
ROB MARCIANO: Meanwhile, several states along the Pacific are on high alert as Hurricane Polo spins, one of the strongest ever recorded, fueled by the epic El Niño.
This was the view from inside the eye of this now Category 4 storm, part of its moisture streaming into the Southwest, now causing dangerous inland flooding in New Mexico.
Back in Virginia Beach, Trey Coates and his family are in town for this weekend's Neptune Festival.
They say they're not going anywhere.
We've been battling the conditions, honestly.
I had to hold the door open, almost flew-- I got sand all over my face.
And just as we speak, the last few minutes, some of those vendors from that festival for the weekend beginning to build their structures, hoping it will hold on to this wind or this wind will die.
But it shows no signs of doing that.
The water now coming up and covering this beach.
And that's going to be the calling card, at least here in the Mid-Atlantic.
And that is coastal flooding all the way up to Delmarva, into New Jersey, and potentially much of the Northeast as well.
That on top of waves that could be 6 to 12 feet, winds 50 miles an hour or better.
And there, you see your warnings.
As far as what we think this storm is going to do-- it will strengthen and expand over the next 24 hours, then ride parallel up the Jersey coastline, impacting Long Island and then New England.
Rain, yes, a big surge of water, and wind that could be damaging.
But if it takes the other model, the GFS solution, it would be a lesser blow, at least to New York City.
We're certainly hoping for that.
But Eastern New England looks to be getting it.
Polo, big-time storm in the Pacific.
But now we have Nolo.
And that is going to threaten Hawaii, not just that, probably hit the Big Island over the weekend with potentially Category 2 or 3 winds.
And, Tony, they are still recovering from a big hurricane just a little over a month ago.
Not what they need in Hawaii.
No, not at all.
Rob, thank you very much.
Now to something that hasn't happened in more than a decade-- an official state visit to the White House from Chinese leader, Xi Jinping.
And there is much for the two leaders to cover, from AI regulation to the wars in Ukraine and the Middle East.
But how much of it we're going to see-- that is an open question tonight.
Nancy Cordes has the latest.
NANCY CORDES: Not content to wait at the White House, President Trump choppered to Joint Base Andrews this afternoon to greet Chinese President Xi Jinping.
It's the first time a US president has made that gesture for a foreign head of state since 1962.
We're doing very well with China.
And President Xi and I have a good relationship.
NANCY CORDES: The US and China are at odds over AI, trade, and most importantly, Iran.
Trump, stop fawning over strongmen.
Stop calling Xi a great gentleman.
NANCY CORDES: Lawmakers from both sides urged Trump to dial back the warm welcome.
His guest is a brutal, unelected, and oppressive dictator.
NANCY CORDES: The two men are set to sit down tomorrow, but video of the historic meeting may be sparse, as the five US TV networks continue to hold off on providing pooled coverage after Trump banned three major outlets from the White House.
They're fake news.
NANCY CORDES: In an emergency hearing this afternoon, Federal Judge Timothy Kelly said, quote, "I think it's fair to say that the process laid out for the White House in previous cases wasn't followed here."
I think the judge was very skeptical of the Trump administration's arguments here.
NANCY CORDES: CBS News Legal Analyst Jessica Levinson.
This is a case where there's a lot of evidence to indicate that the Trump administration is doing exactly what the First Amendment protects against, which is the government picking winners and losers based on who they like and whose speech they like and who they don't.
NANCY CORDES: The judge is expected to make a decision within the next few days about whether to let these three outlets back onto White House grounds temporarily as the case plays out.
Tony?
We'll keep covering it.
Nancy, thank you.
Now let's bring in Face the Nation moderator and chief foreign affairs correspondent, Margaret Brennan.
Margaret, great to have you here.
So the president is rolling out the red carpet for the Chinese president, some say a little bit too much red carpet.
But what are you expecting?
Well, Tony, whenever the two most powerful men in the world meet, there's typically a lot of picture-rich choreography.
China's media state's controlled.
They want this.
But this time, it's different.
The pictures won't be, as Nancy just told you, beamed around the world in the same way.
And that's of concern to some of the Chinese officials I spoke with, in part because Xi Jinping lands here feeling he has the upper hand in the competition with the US, according to multiple Asian diplomats.
Trump needs China to stop buying Iranian oil.
He wants them to stop providing intelligence to Tehran.
China has also cornered the market on a really critical set of ingredients for US-made weapons and technology.
On the other hand, the question for Trump is whether he wants to extend, and for how long, the trade truce with China.
And, of course, there are two Americans being wrongfully detained.
You mentioned Iran there.
Another extraordinary moment at the UN today-- the Iranian president here, at war with the US, and yet, here on US soil, giving a speech.
What stood out to you?
Well, just a few months ago, he was in a bunker, sheltering from US airstrikes, and now he's standing in the middle of New York City.
That, in and of itself, is extraordinary.
Also extraordinary, President Trump's language yesterday when he said he wants to possibly annihilate Iran.
This is an institution built to avoid war.
But Iran's president took to the podium, and he had similar bluster.
He said Iran will never surrender its civilian nuclear program.
He also held up pictures of about what he said were 150 children killed there in airstrikes in the beginning of the war.
But behind the scenes, I'm told both sides still are trying to find a way to negotiate.
They said there was a good meeting, is how the president characterized it.
Margaret, great to have you here.
Appreciate it.
And we'll see you this Sunday, of course, on Face the Nation.
And there's news tonight about the USS Lincoln strike group, which recently left the war zone in the Middle East after a marathon deployment there.
We previously reported on concerns about the mental health of the sailors.
And our Charlie D'Agata is here with an update.
Charlie, good evening.
Good evening, Tony.
So, according to a letter from the Navy's acting secretary, there were eight suicide attempts by sailors aboard the USS Abraham Lincoln strike group during that long 10-month deployment.
Now, that strike group includes multiple ships.
And, notably, they were taking part in combat operations against Iran for much of that time.
Now, as you said, you'll recall the Lincoln was plagued by supply issues during its deployment.
Family members also raised the alarm about morale and mental health of the sailors because of that time on board without a break.
So in that letter, the acting Navy secretary wrote that no service members killed themselves during the deployment.
Tony?
Well, that's good news.
Charlie, thank you very much.
For the third time now, all in less than a week, a military fighter jet has crashed during a training mission.
Today it was a British Royal Air Force jet that went down in Wales, narrowly missing buildings there.
And it follows recent crashes of two US F-16s.
Leigh Kiniry is following this from our London Bureau.
LEIGH KINIRY: Tony, you can see the Hawk 2 jet struggling to gain altitude in this video posted on social media.
Moments later, the two pilots eject from the cockpit.
And less than 20 seconds after that, the plane nosedives into a field, exploding into a fireball.
It narrowly missed nearby homes.
Witnesses said they noticed trouble from the start, describing fire coming from the jet, but the two airmen landed safely nearby.
They were treated just for minor injuries, and no one else was hurt in the crash.
The Royal Air Force have not yet said what they believe went wrong.
But the Hawk T2 is used to train fighter pilots.
It can reach speeds of up to 650 miles an hour.
Tonight, the Hawk jets are temporarily grounded while the Royal Air Force investigates this crash.
Tony?
Leigh, thank you very much.
We turn now to Ohio and the trial of a former American Idol contestant accused of murdering his wife.
On the stand today, his former girlfriend-- and it did not seem to go well for the defense.
CBS's Ian Lee has the update.
IAN LEE: Today, 24-year-old Alleigha Botner, a former church intern and Caleb Flynn's one-time lover, took the stand.
I hate him.
IAN LEE: Prosecutors had Botner read aloud some of the more than 100,000 messages between the two during their affair.
At first, it was, I want her dead.
I wish she was gone.
And then it was, if I could kill her and not go to jail, I would.
IAN LEE: The prosecution says Flynn's affair with Botner drove him to murder his wife, Ashley, a charge he denies.
Prosecutors also showed a video Flynn sent to Botner, highlighting his obsession with her.
CALEB FLYNN: Anybody who's listening, I love Aaliyah Botner.
IAN LEE: On the stand, Botner recalled the moment she learned of Ashley Flynn's death.
My heart started pounding.
And in my mind, it seemed like too much of a coincidence that the day he's divorcing her, she's just dead, all of a sudden.
IAN LEE: The former American Idol contestant and pastor is accused of shooting his wife twice while she slept in their Ohio home in February and attempted to cover up the killing by staging a burglary.
A gun was never recovered.
Investigators became suspicious of his claim by the lack of outside damage to a garage door.
It wasn't what I would expect to see on a forced entry type of scenario.
IAN LEE: Flynn claims he was in another room when his wife was murdered.
But there are questions around why the couple's two dogs, known for being highly energetic, remains silent with an alleged intruder inside the house.
Tony?
Ian, thank you.
Dolly Parton's nephew, the one who informed all of us about her death, is now under a court order to stay out of the majority of the business dealings she left behind.
Nicole Valdes is in Nashville with the new allegations.
This video announcement is something Dolly asked of me years ago, before I fully absorbed it as a future reality.
NICOLE VALDES: The man who told the world that Dolly Parton died, her nephew, Bryan Seaver, is now at the heart of a messy legal battle.
Parton's longtime manager, Danny Nozell, and the LLC that manages many of Parton's businesses, claims Seaver, who headed Parton's security, had become, quote, "emboldened and relentless."
The legal filings accuse him of trying to extort Parton's estate and making "terroristic threats, harassment, and intimidation" and sending threatening texts to Nozell and staff members, saying things like, "I'm going to destroy the entire brand," and "I'm going to set up a podcast dedicated to ruining Dolly's brand partnerships."
I mean, they literally call him a terrorist in this complaint.
The text messages that they've provided do paint a picture, a very scary picture, of, really, an unhinged person.
However, I will say that it's light on the technical legal details.
NICOLE VALDES: According to court documents, Nozell says Seaver was terminated last week and Parton's team cut ties with his security company.
One of the threats Seaver's accused of making says, quote, "I'm not an entertainment person, I'm a killer."
Late today, a Nashville judge granted the restraining order Nozell and the LLC requested against Seaver.
And CBS News has reached out to Dolly's estate, Nozell, and Seaver.
None have responded.
But according to multiple reports, including one from TMZ, Seaver denies the claims in this petition, saying his messages were taken out of context, that they were not threats.
But he did add, quote, "Most of the comments, I stand by."
Meanwhile, Dolly's new hotel and museum here in Nashville are set to open next week.
Tony?
All right.
Nicole, thank you.
Still ahead on the broadcast tonight, the dozens of people who claim they rode a Six Flags roller coaster and walked away with life-altering brain injuries.
California's Six Flags Magic Mountain describes its X2 roller coaster as a ride for the ultimate daredevil and, quote, "downright scary."
But is it also dangerous?
Lawyers for more than a hundred people say the coaster left them with traumatic brain injuries.
Our Carter Evans reports.
CARTER EVANS: Reaching speeds up to 76 miles per hour with seats that spin 360 degrees, the X2 is Six Flags Magic Mountain's signature roller coaster.
But for Naomi Greer-Wilkinson, that thrill may have come at a devastating cost.
When we got there, they told us to prepare for end of life.
CARTER EVANS: Her parents allege that Naomi's ride on the X2 in July landed her in the hospital with a traumatic brain injury.
She's still on a ventilator.
Naomi had no idea that she was signing up for something that could potentially rip the veins in her skull.
CARTER EVANS: The Dordick law corporation represents more than 100 people who say they've suffered traumatic brain injuries after riding the X2, including Michael Wilk, an attorney who said he underwent two brain surgeries to stop the internal bleeding.
I struggle for words.
I don't necessarily think clearly.
CARTER EVANS: As a result of his injuries, Wilk says he's on disability and doesn't know if he'll ever be able to practice law again.
I didn't think take a ride in a roller coaster at a legitimate theme park and end up with brain bleed and multiple surgeries in your head.
And you're not the only one.
And I'm not the only one.
CARTER EVANS: In 2022, 22-year-old Christopher Hawley died after riding the X2.
His family settled a lawsuit with the amusement park earlier this year.
That's what makes me angry.
They had been sued at least a year before I was injured.
They knew.
CARTER EVANS: Now, Wilk told me the force of the roller coaster slammed his head against the headrest, causing severe pain.
That's X2 behind me.
Six Flags closed it in July.
And today, the company declined to comment on the pending lawsuits.
Tony?
Carter, thank you.
Coming up next, the close-call lightning strike caught on camera.
A lightning bolt hit interstate 84 in Utah last night, the moment captured on dashcam video from a driver, who said it was louder than you can imagine.
And it nearly zapped a box truck just ahead of him.
What the driver of that truck said when it happened-- probably not safe for TV.
A golden retriever puppy in Northern California showed off some leadership skills recently, taking this horse for a little walk.
The horse didn't resist a bit, possibly because it thinks of itself as just a big dog, which may be what the puppy is thinking too.
Up next, a historic home run ball and the birthday girl who appreciated it for what it was.
We're back with the good stuff tonight, a reminder of both the innocence of children and the intended purpose of a baseball.
It comes courtesy of this historic home run last night off the bat of a Eugenio Suárez, now just the 10th active player with 350 homers or more.
And somewhere out there in left field was a girl celebrating her sixth birthday, who ended up with that priceless souvenir.
For a moment, it felt like the whole stadium was cheering for little Calia and probably thinking, wow, that ball has got to be worth some serious money.
But what does a kid care about money?
A baseball, after all, is intended to be thrown.
COMMENTATOR: Eugenio Suárez's 350th career home run-- and throwing it back.
Oh my goodness.
CARTER EVANS: The Braves broadcast crew rushed out to see what she was thinking.
And her answer here is just perfect.
Why did you throw it back?
I don't know.
I just want to throw it.
She just wanted to throw it.
You see, for all those cheering adults, the best part of catching a home run ball is keeping it or maybe selling it.
But for a kid like Calia, after eight innings of watching other people play baseball, the best part was the game itself.
Finally, it was her turn to play.
That's another day in America.
I'm Tony Dokoupil.
For all of us here at CBS News, thank you for watching.
We'll see you right back here tomorrow.
Good night.